Behzad Nouri

IT Business Analyst - Data Scientist

Motivated, teamwork-oriented and solution-minded IT business analyst, with significant experience in managing and doing successful IT projects. Having hands-on experience and proper knowledge in data analysis, statistics and machine learning, possessing a master in IT management and studying a second master in data science at KULeuven.

nuri.behzad@gmail.com

+32-483 32 69 68

Luxemburg City

in linkedin.com/in/behzad-nouri-69a49591

github.com/behnouri

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist CLdN

04/2021 - Present

Luxemburg

Achievements/Tasks

- Develop and deploy machine learning algorithms to forecast demand. Employing different time series analysis and machine learning techniques.
- Develop interactive data products and reports using dash/plotly framework in python.
- Develop software toolset to automate processes using python.

Data Analyst - Python Developer for ALCAPAS Project KULeuven - LIRIS

08/2020 - 09/2020

Leuven

Achievements/Tasks

- Preprocess the data, including joining tables, cleaning and finding missing values using Pandas and Numpy
- Aggregate data and do visualizations using mathplotlib and seaborn libraries
- Write modules and functions to get batch jobs automatically done

Business Development Lead Hillavas

05/2016 - 07/2019

Tehran

Achievements/Tasks

- Identify new business opportunities including new markets, growth areas, trends, customers, products and services
- Follow-up new business opportunities and setup teams for doing new business development projects
- Arrange business development meetings and negotiate with stakeholders
- Assign and lead product managers for new products

Business Systems Analyst Mellat Insurance

04/2014 - 04/2016

Tehran

Achievements/Tasks

- Examine current IT systems and document the processes
- Interview with users and read the documents (requirement gathering) for systems redesign
- Design new systems, design databases and document technical specifications
- Communicate with programmers, managers and users in order to successfully implement and deploy new systems

SKILLS

Python

MSSQL Server

MYSOL

Machine Learning techniques

Spark

Html, CSS, JavaScript

 \circ

System Analysis & Design

Database Design

Rapid Prototyping

Product Management

Business Development

11 December, 2021 Page 1 of 2

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst

Fara Co.

04/2012 - 03/2014 Tehran

Achievements/Tasks

- Collect data to understand the as-is situation of client organizations
- Analyze as-is processes and propose improvements
- Identify Issues and propose solutions as business case

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Business Engineering (Data Science - Marketing) KULeuven

2019 - 2021 Leuven

M.Sc. in Information Technology Management

University of Tehran

2011 - 2014 Tehran

B.Sc. in Industrial Engineering Ferdowsi University of Mashhad

2006 - 2011 Mashhad

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Master's Thesis

 Learning Analytics - application of data science in a blended learning environment toward the implementation of adaptive learning paths for student activation and assessment

Big data project

Online streaming analytics for text classification, using Spark

Advanced analytics project

 prediction of laptop price range based on device specs (award winner team for our best results due to advanced machine learning techniques employed)

Master's Thesis (undertaken in 1st masters program)

 Designing A New Algorithm To Categorize And Analyze The Research Trends In The Field Of Artificial Intelligence: The Combination Of Text Mining And Bibliometrics

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Co-Founder - Growth Lead

Rasmionline.com

04/2018 - 07/2019

CO-Founder - Product Manager

Tarjomano.com

09/2015 - 09/2015

REFERENCES

Morteza Davari -Assistant Professor at Skema Business School -visiting teacher at KULeuven

Contact: morteza.davari@kuleuven.be - +32 486 33 14 62

Meysam Mirzazadeh - IT Manager at Mellat Insurance Co.

Contact: mirzazadeh@mellatinsurance.com

11 December, 2021 Page 2 of 2